{"tossups": [{"question": "<em>This city's first major military victory occurred at the Battle of Tegyra.</em> A foreign tyrant of this city dismissively remarked \"urgent business for tomorrow\" after receiving a letter exposing a plot led by seven crossdressing conspirators, including Pelopidas. This city won the Battle of Mantinea and the Battle of Leuctra under the leadership of Epaminondas. This city used a force of 300 lovers, the Sacred Band. For the point, name this ancient Greek city which was tormented by the Sphinx in the Oedipus myth.", "answer": "<b><u>Thebes</u></b> [or <b><u>Thebai</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>Participants in this event were aided by the National Urban League.</em> Robert Sengstacke Abbott's <em>Chicago Defender</em> newspaper encouraged this event by calling for a \"drive.\" This event resulted in riots during the Red Summer, and it mirrored the earlier exoduster movement. The most famous series of paintings by Jacob Lawrence depicts this event. Participants in this event were often sharecroppers who left the \"black belt\" region. For the point, name this twentieth century movement of millions of African Americans to northern cities.", "answer": "<b><u>Great Migration</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>Richard the Lionheart supposedly created silver chains to imprison a member of this family</em> <em>after conquering Cyprus.</em> A woman who married into this family, Anna Dalassene, served as de facto ruler while her son was on campaign. This family established the Empire of Trebizond, and its best-known member fought Robert Guiscard at Dyrrachium. In an effort to fend off the Seljuk Turks, that ruler from this dynasty invited people like Godfrey of Bouillon (<b>pr. bwee-YONE</b>) and Bohemond of Taranto to his court after asking Urban II for aid. For the point, name this Byzantine dynasty that included Alexius I.", "answer": "<b><u>Komnenos</u></b> [or <b><u>Comnenus</u></b>; or <b><u>Komnenoi</u></b>; or <b><u>Komnenids</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "SL"}, {"question": "<em>This monarch employed a network of diplomatic agents called the King's Secret.</em> This king faced a strike of judges in response to the taxation policies of his minister, Rene de Maupeou. The Cellamare Conspiracy attempted to replace this king's regent, Philippe d'Orleans. This king fired the economist John Law after the Mississippi Bubble and was known as the \"well-beloved.\" The dying words \"After us, the deluge\" are attributed to this king's mistress Madame du Pompadour. For the point, name this king whose successor was executed during the French Revolution.", "answer": "<b><u>Louis XV</u></b> [or <b><u>Louis</u></b> the <b><u>Well-Beloved</u></b> before mentioned; prompt on <b><u>Louis</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>This leader resided in a city known as the \"Versailles of the Jungle,\" Gbadolite</em>. This man formed the political party MPR, whose ideals were established in the Manifesto of N'Sele. He called for foreign aid in repelling forces in a breakaway province in Shaba I and Shaba II. This leader sought to move his country away from colonial legacy which included renaming his country's capital from Leopoldville to Kinshasa. This man rose to power after leading a coup against Patrice Lumumba and deposing Joseph Kasa-Vubu a few years later. For the point, name this dictator who renamed his country Zaire.", "answer": "<b><u>Mobutu</u></b> Sese Seko Kuku Ngbendu wa Za Banga [or Joseph-Desire <b><u>Mobutu</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "JL"}, {"question": "<em>Cheryl Hopwood successfully challenged this university's law school's affirmative action</em> <em>program.</em> This university's law school's whites-only admission standards led to the creation of the Thurgood Marshall School of Law, which was found not to be \"separate but equal\" in <em>Sweatt</em> <em>v. Painter</em>. In 2013, the Supreme Court remanded to the Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals a case alleging that this university's admission policies were not \"narrowly tailored.\" In 1966, this university saw a massacre take place when Charles Whitman shot people from a tower on its campus. For the point, name this state university sued by Abigail Fisher in the South Central US.", "answer": "University of <b><u>Texas</u></b> [or University of <b><u>Texas</u></b> at Austin]  {III}", "metadata": "DW"}, {"question": "<em>Items presented during this event included a telegraph and a miniature railway.</em> The traveller John Manjiro provided assistance during this event, which was preceded by James Biddle's failed attempt at the same goal. This event resulted in the appointment of Townsend Harris to a new consulship. During this event, the appearance of the Black Ships forced the signing of the Convention of Kanagawa. For the point, name this event in which a US Commodore forcefully opened an isolationist island nation to foreign trade.", "answer": "Matthew Calbraith <b><u>Perry</u></b>'s expedition to Japan [or anything indicating the US \"opening\" <b><u>Japan</u></b> to trade; or Convention of <b><u>Kanagawa</u></b> before mentioned]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>A doctrine promulgated by this pope was protested by Johann Joseph Ignaz von D\u00f6llinger.</em> Early in his reign, this pope had to flee to Gaeta. This pope issued the encyclical <em>Quanta Cura,</em> and his bull <em>Ineffabilis Deus</em> declared the Immaculate Conception to be dogma. This pope declared himself a \u201cprisoner in the Vatican\u201d after Italian troops occupied Rome. This pope convened the First Vatican Council, which defined papal infallibility, and issued the <em>Syllabus of</em> <em>Errors.</em> For the point, name this longest reigning pope.", "answer": "<b><u>Pius IX</u></b> [or Giovanni Maria <b><u>Mastai-Ferretti</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>Several structures in this landform have an almost-straight \"jogged axis\" layout.</em> A discovery made in this landform made by Neapolitan strongman Giovanni Batista Belzoni in October 1817 was later rebuilt in full in the British museum. El-Qurn is a peak overlooking this place. 63 sub-locales within this area are denoted by KV numbers. Starting in 1914, Lord Carnarvon sponsored excavations in this geographic location led by Howard Carter. For the points, name this area across from Thebes off the Nile, where many New Kingdom pharaohs are buried.", "answer": "<b><u>Valley of the Kings</u></b> [or <b><u>Wadi al-Muluk</u></b>; or the <b><u>Great Field</u></b>; or <b><u>Ta-sekhet-Maat</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>This man described being attacked by a mob in Venezuela in his book Six Crises</em>. While this man was praised for his speeches at the American National Exhibition, his superior joked needing a week to think of any ideas this man had.He claimed that his wife wore a \"respectable Republican cloth coat.\" This man vigorously debated Nikita Khrushchev in the \"Kitchen Debate.\" In a speech, this man said he would not return \"a little cocker spaniel\" and defended the use of a slush fund. For the point, name this man who gave the 1952 \"Checkers speech\" and who was Vice-President under Dwight Eisenhower.", "answer": "Richard Milhous <b><u>Nixon</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>A song by this band prompted Alan Keyes to jump into a mosh pit at the 2000 Iowa Caucus.</em> This band called for the release of activist Mumia Abu-Jamal in a song that states \"More for Gore or the son of a drug lord? None of the above.\" Following 9/11, Clear Channel suggested banning this band's entire catalog from radio airplay. The cover of this band's self-titled 1992 album depicts a monk burning himself. Songs like \"Guerrilla Radio\" appear on their album <em>The</em> <em>Battle of Los Angeles</em>. For the point, name this band known for politically-charged songs such as \"Bulls on Parade\" and \"Killing in the Name.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Rage Against the Machine</u></b> [or <b><u>RATM</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>This event was partly caused by the capture of one participant by Robert Guiscard at the</em> <em>Battle of Civitate.</em> This event occurred due to the undiplomatic actions of Humbert of Silva Candida. Attempts to reverse this event included the Second Council of Lyon and the Council of Florence-Ferrara. In this event, issues like the <em>filioque</em> phrase in the Nicene Creed led Michael Cerularius and Pope Leo IX to mutually excommunicate each other. For the point, name this event which split Christianity into Roman Catholic and Eastern Orthodox branches.", "answer": "<b><u>Great</u><u>Schism</u></b> [Prompt on \u201c<b><u>Schism</u></b>;\u201d do not accept \"Western Schism\"]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>This athlete is not from Memphis, but he joined Matt Vasgersian and Jim Ross to commentate</em> <em>for the short-lived XFL</em>. This athlete used the catchphrase \"win if you can, lose if you must, but always cheat\" and was once the Mayor of Brooklyn Park. Chris Kyle, the protagonist of <em>American Sniper</em>, claimed to have punched this athlete in the face at a bar. Known as the \"Body,\" this member of the Reform Party acted as a special guest referee at a WWF pay-per-view while simultaneously holding public office. For the point, name this former professional wrestler who served as Governor of Minnesota.", "answer": "Jesse <b><u>Ventura</u></b> [or James <b><u>Janos</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>The American envoy William Gates visited and wrote articles about this man.</em> This man was aided by the political theorist Antonio D\u00edaz Soto y Gama, and adopted the slogan <em>\u201cTierra y</em> <em>Libertad,\u201d</em> or \u201cLand and Liberty.\u201d He was killed in an ambush after Jes\u00fas Guajardo organized a secret meeting with him in Chinameca, Morelos. This leader of the Liberation Army of the South proposed the Plan of Ayala, which was rejected by Venustiano Carranza\u2019s Constitutionalists. For the point, name this <em>mestizo</em> who led a guerrilla army during the Mexican Revolution.", "answer": "Emiliano <b><u>Zapata</u></b> [do not accept <b><u>Zapatista</u></b>s]  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>Planning for this event was done in the home of Michael Fortier.</em> On the day of this event, its main perpetrator wore a shirt reading \"Sic semper tyrannis\" and carried a copy of <em>The Turner</em> <em>Diaries</em> with him. One of the motivations behind this event was the death of Randy Weaver at Ruby Ridge. This event was carried out on the two-year anniversary of the Waco Massacre. It resulted in the destruction of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building. For the point, name this terrorist attack carried out by Terry Nichols and Timothy McVeigh in the Sooner State.", "answer": "<b><u>Oklahoma City</u> </b>bombing {II}", "metadata": "JL"}, {"question": "<em>One unit of this type is commemorated by Bertel Thorvaldsen\u2019s Lion Monument.</em> One unit of this type was destroyed when it bought time for their leader to escape to safety via the Passetto. Two thirds of one unit of this type was destroyed in the insurrection of 10 August 1792 at the Tuileries Palace. In 1998, Alois Estermann, a leader of this unit was murdered by one of its members. The Medici colours are used in a striped red, yellow, and blue ceremonial uniform of one of these units that was apocryphally designed by Michelangelo. For the point, name these units, one of which serves as the bodyguards of the Pope.", "answer": "Pontifical <b><u>Swiss Guard</u></b>s [or <b><u>Gardes Suisse</u></b>; or Pontificia <b><u>Cohors Helvetica</u></b>; or <b><u>Cohors</u></b> Pedestris <b><u>Helvetiorum</u></b> a Sacra Custodia Pontificis; prompt on <b><u>Guards</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "<em>This artist painted smoking ruins behind Baldwin I in his Entry of the Crusaders in</em> <em>Constantinople.</em> This artist painted the legendary last king of the Assyrians ordering all of his concubines killed. In another of his paintings, an Ottoman soldier on a rearing horse surveys the grim results of a massacre on a Greek island. This painter of <em>The Death of Sardanapalus</em> and <em>The</em> <em>Massacre at Chios</em> (<b>pr. KEE-ohs</b>) painted a woman holding a musket it one hand and the tricolor in another in his representation of the July Revolution. For the point, name this French painter of <em>Liberty Leading the People</em>.", "answer": "Eugene <b><u>Delacroix</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "EA"}, {"question": "<em>An engagement in this campaign was mockingly dubbed \u201cThe Woodstock Races\u201d for the</em> <em>speedy retreat of the losing side.</em> William McKinley personally intercepted stragglers, and the winning general made a famed ride from Winchester, during the last battle of this campaign. Despite a surprise attack led by Jubal Early, the Confederates lost the culminating battle of this campaign at Cedar Creek. This campaign, known simply as \u201cThe Burning,\u201d may have inspired Sherman\u2019s scorched earth tactics during the March to the Sea later in the year. For the point, name this 1864 campaign in which Philip Sheridan rampaged through Western Virginia.", "answer": "<b><u>Shenandoah Valley</u></b> Campaign [accept <b><u>Red October</u></b>; accept The <b><u>Burning</u></b> before it is mentioned]  {III}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "<em>This scientist had to deal with so much harassment that his mother contacted Himmler\u2019s</em> <em>mother to try to give him a break</em>. This member of the Uranium club travelled to Copenhagen to discuss physics with a colleague, which is the subject of a Michael Frayn play. A statement named for this man explains why spectral lines have finite widths. This man justified one of his ideas with a thought experiment which shows a gamma ray microscope must have limits to the precision in which it can determine the position and momentum of an electron. For the point, name this German physicist who names an uncertainty principle.", "answer": "Werner <b><u>Heisenberg</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "<em>One of these institutions was reformed by Gates v. Collier, which ended the use of the trusty</em> <em>system at Parchman Farm.</em> Critical Resistance is a movement opposed to the \"industrial complex\" involving these institutions. The \"Revolving Door\" ad attacked Michael Dukakis's policies on these institutions following the actions of Willie Horton. Tear gas was used to end a hostage situation in one of these places during the tenure of Governor Nelson Rockefeller. For the point, name this sort of institution where the Attica Riot occurred in 1971.", "answer": "<b><u>prison</u></b>s [or <b><u>jail</u></b>s; or <b><u>penitentiarie</u></b>s; or <b><u>correctional facilitie</u></b>s; or obvious equivalents]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>One leader of this political party was criticized for attempting to appeal to young voters by</em> <em>wearing a baseball cap at the Notting Hill Fair.</em> This party was led by William Hague after the loss of a prime minister who pulled his country out of the Exchange Rate Mechanism on Black Wednesday. Michael Haseltine challenged another leader of this party, who lost favor after trying to institute a Community Charge. That leader of this party was nicknamed \u201cmilk-snatcher\u201d while serving as Education Secretary under Ted Heath. For the point, name this political party, which at various times was led by John Major and Margaret Thatcher.", "answer": "<b><u>Conservative</u></b> and Unionist Party [or <b><u>Tories</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "EM"}, {"question": "<em>This event was the subject of David McCullough's first book</em>. This event led to a trial where a group was successfully defended by member Philander Knox. It failed to destroy the South Bridge, which did result in debris catching fire and starting a 30 acre inferno. Part of the blame went to a hunting club whose membership included Henry Clay Frick and Andrew Carnegie. This event led to the first major relief effort by the American Red Cross and was caused by the failure of the South Fork Dam. For the point, name this 1889 flood which killed thousands in a Pennsylvania town.", "answer": "<b><u>Johnstown Flood</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>William Makepeace Thackeray's \"A May Day Ode\" was written to celebrate the first day of</em> <em>this event.</em> The first America's Cup was held in conjunction with this event. Douglas Jerrold, writing under the pseudonym \"Amelia Mouser\" for <em>Punch</em> magazine, coined the name of this event's central building. That building was constructed by Charles Fox, who previously invented the railroad switch. This event was the brainchild of Prince Albert. For the point, name this 1851 event that kicked off the tradition of the World's Fair and is sometimes named for the glass building that was at its center.", "answer": "<b><u>Great Exhibition</u></b> of the Works of Industry of All Nations [or <b><u>Crystal Palace</u> </b>Exhibition]  {II}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>This man ruined the economy of Poland by spreading counterfeit currency</em>. This man first commanded an army at the Battle of Mollwitz, although he fled before the battle was over. His childhood friend Hans Hermann von Katte was executed after they attempted to flee the country together. His father, the unstable Frederick William I, created the powerful military that this man commanded during the War of Austrian Succession and Seven Years War. For the point, which enlightened despot and longtime friend of Voltaire ruled Prussia for much of the 18th century?", "answer": "<b><u>Frederick the Great</u></b> [or <b><u>Frederick II</u></b> of Prussia; prompt on <b><u>Frederick</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "<em>The tune of this song is used in another song that begins \u201cLet\u2019s denounce the old world, Let\u2019s</em> <em>shake the dust from our feet.\u201d</em> The tune of this song is used in a Russian revolutionary song entitled \u201cThe Worker\u2019s [this song].\u201d One verse of this song exhorts its listeners not to spare the accomplices of the Marquis of Bouille. The refrain of this song exhorts listeners to \u201cForm your battalions, march on, march on.\u201d A unit of particularly enthusiastic singers of this song caused it to be named after that unit\u2019s home city. For the point, name this national anthem of France.", "answer": "La <b><u>Marseillaise</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "<em>Giovanni Giustiniani was wounded while leading a contingent from this polity in the defense</em> <em>of Constantinople.</em> At the Battle of Crecy, rain ruined the crossbow strings of mercenaries from this city. Benedetto Zaccaria helped this city defeat Pisa at the Battle of Meloria, but it later lost the War of Chioggia to a different rival. This owner of Constantinople\u2019s Galata district was home to the admiral Andrea Doria, and it controlled Corsica until the 1700s. For the point, name this Italian maritime republic based in a Ligurian city, which rivaled Venice and was the birthplace of Christopher Columbus.", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Genoa</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "SL"}, {"question": "<em>A non-Byzantine book named after the Secret History of this man\u2019s people describes his</em> <em>broken friendship with Jamukha.</em> This conqueror of the Naimans and Merkits promulgated the unifying law code called the Yassa. Although illiterate, this man started the use of the Uyghur (<b>pr. WEE-ghur</b>) script for his people\u2019s language. This man conquered the Khwarezmian Empire and the Western Xia Dynasty. His oldest son Jochi\u2019s questionable paternity led this man to name his third son Ogedei his successor as Great Khan. For the point, name this founder of the Mongol Empire.", "answer": "<b><u>Genghis</u></b> Khan [or <b><u>Chingis</u></b> Khan or <b><u>Temujin</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "<em>During this battle, a defensive line was formed westward from the Elsenborn Ridge.</em> One site of fighting during this battle was Saint-Vith. George Patton kept a promise to relieve a siege at this battle within 48 hours, and then began a counterattack. During this battle, Anthony McAuliffe replied \u201cNuts\u201d at the siege of Bastogne. This battle was an attempt to cut off Allied supply lines running from Antwerp to the Ardennes Forest. For the point, name this battle named for the wedge the German attack drove into American lines.", "answer": "Battle of the <b><u>Bulge</u></b> [or Operation <b><u>Watch on the Rhine</u></b> or Unternehmen <b><u>Wacht am</u></b> <b><u>Rhein</u></b>; accept Battle of the <b><u>Ardennes</u></b> before mentioned]  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>This man claimed to have solved the problem of longitude by observing a conjunction of the</em> <em>Moon with Mars.</em> This explorer split from an expedition searching for the \u201cCoast of Pearls\u201d in order to look for the Strait of Catigara. Ralph Waldo Emerson called this first Pilot Major of Spain a \u201cpickle dealer.\u201d Historians still dispute the authorship of two letters from this man to Pier Soderini, as well as his pamphlet <em>Mundus Novus</em>. For the point, Martin Waldseemuller later regretted attaching what Florentine explorer\u2019s name to a newly-discovered continent?", "answer": "Amerigo <b><u>Vespucci</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "DW"}, {"question": "<em>The killer of this hero names a cancelled operation of the Spring Offensive</em>. This hero was killed by a figure who saw where a linden leaf landed on him; that killer of this hero was Hagen. The Rosamund stone tells the story of this hero. In the Anglosphere, this hero\u2019s name is given to a defensive structure officially called the <em>Westwall</em> that ran parallel to the Maginot Line. This hero kills Reginn, his foster father, after learning the language of birds by drinking the blood of the dragon Fafnir, who this hero slew. For the point, name this German hero of the Ring Cycle.", "answer": "<b><u>Siegfried</u></b> [or <b><u>Sigurd</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "<em>An era taking up much of the 1970s in this country was called the Banzerato, a name derived</em> <em>from its dictator Hugo Banzer.</em> Prisoners of war in this country built the Unduavi-Yolosa highway in the 1930s, which is one-way and has an extremely high fatality rate. In the early 80s, its economy collapsed due to a fall in the price of its dominant export, tin. The Aymara people make up a plurality of this country. For the point, name this coca-growing country led recently by Evo Morales in central South America.", "answer": "Plurinational State of <b><u>Bolivia</u></b> [or Estado Plurinacional de <b><u>Bolivia</u></b>; or <b><u>Buliwya</u></b>; or <b><u>Wuliwya</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>Stan Greenberg wrote about this politician's support among Macomb County auto workers</em>. This man once said \"if the job were finished, I might have thought twice about seeking reelection.\" This man was supported by a commercial that began with the cryptic line \"There is a bear in the woods.\" He quipped that he would not \"exploit\" his \"opponent's youth and inexperience\" during a campaign. This man ran a successful advertisement proclaiming it was \"morning again in America.\" For the point, name this man who defeated Walter Mondale in 1984 to win re-election as President.", "answer": "Ronald <b><u>Reagan</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>Aaron Burr\u2019s Morning Chroniclepublished this man\u2019s political letters that were written</em> <em>under the name of Jonathan Oldstyle</em>. The most popular 19th century biography of Christopher Columbus was penned by this author. This author wrote historical stories, such as \u201cThe Legend of the Arabian Astrologer\u201d and \u201cGovernor Manco and the Soldier\u201d in his collection <em>Tales of the</em> <em>Alhambra</em>. One of his stories is set in Tarry Town and features a Hessian trooper who terrorizes Ichabod Crane. For the point, name this author of \u201cThe Legend of Sleepy Hollow.\u201d", "answer": "Washington <b><u>Irving</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "<em>Ancient geographers identified cliffs on this landform with the cliffs that the mythical bandit</em> <em>Sciron kicked unsuspecting travelers off.</em> Poseidon was the dedicatee of a set of games here held every four years, the year before the Delphic games. The <em>diolkos,</em> a path going widthwise across this landform, was first commissioned by Periander. Julius Caesar proposed cutting through this feature so boats wouldn't have to be hauled overland across it. For the point, name this narrow band of land separating the Peloponnesus from mainland Greece, which is overseen by a namesake city.", "answer": "<b><u>isthmus</u></b> of <b><u>Corinth</u></b> [prompt on <b><u>isthmus</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>A Japanese version of this discipline was called yenri, or the \u201ccircle method\u201d.</em> George Berkeley (<b>pr. BARK-lee</b>) opposed this discipline on the grounds that it made use of the \u201cghosts of departed quantities<em>.\u201d</em> Karl Weierstrass laid the theoretical foundations for this discipline by proposing the epsilon-delta definition of a center function. Guillaume de L\u2019hopital published a textbook on this subject, which introduced his namesake rule regarding indeterminate forms. Gottfried Leibniz developed the integral form of this mathematical discipline. For the point, name this discipline in which one may take limits and find derivatives.", "answer": "<b><u>calculus</u></b> [prompt on \u201c<b><u>math</u></b>ematics\u201d]  {II}  <b>Extra Tossup - ONLY READ IF A QUESTION IS BOTCHED!</b> <em>President Ulysses S. Grant prevented large numbers of this minority from attacking Canada</em> <em>shortly after the Civil War</em>. New York\u2019s Orange Riots in 1870 and 1871 were caused by denominational differences between members of this minority. A popular historical misconception is that members of this non-black minority were also owned as slaves because many of them immigrated as indentured servants. For the point, name this minority group that immigrated en masse to the United States from the British Isles after an 1845-52 potato famine.  ANSWER: <b><u>Irish</u></b>-Americans [accept <b><u>Fenian</u></b>s during the italicized sentence]  {II}", "metadata": "Ike"}], "bonuses": []}